# lan Dexter D. Marquez

# Linux system administrator

+63 917 887 6260 im@iandexter.net http://www.iandexter.net

Highly skilled IT generalist with more than 10 years extensive experience in handling enterprise IT initiatives while leveraging open source and proprietary solutions. With proven competence in administering Linux and Unix platforms using various automation tools, in tight collaboration with global software development and operations teams in the areas of continuous integration, rapid deployment, and application delivery and support. Certified in Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Microsoft Windows, and ITIL Foundation in IT Service Management.

# **QUALIFICATIONS**

# Bachelor of Science in Computing major in Computer Science, 2011

Technological University of the Philippines, Manila

**Red Hat Certified Engineer**, OCTOBER 2008

ITIL v3 Foundation in IT Service Management, JULY 2008

**Red Hat Certified Technician**, NOVEMBER 2006

**Microsoft Certified Professional**, MAY 2006

Trend Micro Certified Security Expert, JUNE 2006

#### **Interests**

DevOps, PaaS, IaaS, OpenShift, OpenStack, Google App Engine

# Skill areas

- Unix/Linux systems administration (10 years / advanced)
- Infrastructure automation (2 years / proficient)
- Application deployment and support (6 years / advanced)
- Network design, development and administration (5 years / proficient)
- Web design, development and management (3 years / proficient)
- Identity management (2 years / proficient)

### Languages

- Bash/Shell (10 years / advanced)
- Perl (5 years / proficient)
- PHP (3 years / proficient)
- SQL (2 years / proficient)
- Javascript (3 years / proficient)

#### **Platforms**

- Red Hat Enterprise Linux, CentOS, Fedora (10 years / advanced)
- SuSE Linux Enterprise Server (3 years / advanced)
- Ubuntu, Debian (2 years / proficient)
- Sun Solaris, IBM AIX (1 year / basic)
- Microsoft Windows 2003 Server (1 year / basic)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Linux system administrator

**APRIL 2010 TO PRESENT** 

Asian Development Bank (under RCG IT, Inc.)

Maintains AIX, SuSE and Red Hat enterprise Linux servers in the Bank's data center for its mission-critical applications like ERP, data warehousing, financials, and business intelligence. The Asian Development Bank is a multilateral financial institution that provides technical and financial assistance to developing countries.

#### Senior software engineer

MAY 2007 TO APRIL 2010

Accenture

Supported the global identity management and web infrastructure of a leading financial services firm. Accenture is an industry leader in global management consulting, technology services, and outsourcing.

#### Unix system administrator

JANUARY 2007 TO APRIL 2007

Asian Development Bank (under Cytronics, Inc.)

Operated and maintained Unix servers in the Bank's data center. The Asian Development Bank is a multilateral financial institution that provides technical and financial assistance to developing countries.

### Systems engineer

APRIL 2006 TO JANUARY 2007

Trend Micro, Inc.

Provided intermediate-level technical and engineering support for Trend Micro enterprise products as part of its EMEA Technical Support Center infrastructure. Trend Micro is a global leader in anti-virus and security solutions, providing comprehensive enterprise-level services across multiple platforms and customer segments.

#### Linux and web administrator

**JULY 2004 TO MARCH 2006** 

Philippine Rice Research Institute

Managed Linux servers of the corporate intranet in the local and wide area networks, and numerous web-based services for the Institute. Developed a portal for the Open Academy for Philippine Agriculture, the [Pinoy Farmers' Internet](http://www.openacademy.ph). The Philippine Rice Research Institute is a premier research and development facility in Asia that pioneers and promotes rice science and technology.

### **Network administrator**

APRIL 2002 TO JULY 2004

National Irrigation Administration

Designed and implemented the NIA Central Office local area network, and implemented services such as Active Directory, intranet, web, e-mail, and instant messaging. The National Irrigation Administration is the lead Philippine agency that provides irrigation services, development, operation and maintenance.

## Community relations / information assistant FEBRUARY 1999 TO MARCH 2002

National Irrigation Administration

Implemented the public information infrastructure for the Casecnan Multipurpose Irrigation and Power Project (CMIPP), and frequently assigned to IT-related activities. The CMIPP is NIA's flagship project in providing irrigation services to northern Central Luzon and supplementary power to the Luzon grid of the National Power Corporation.